(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-11T01:13:56.049012",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Reine B'Day Classroom - Field Trip: Food & Games with Akai Haato
Attention please, Motherfeathers!
Today, I've got some amazing guests here to celebrate my birthday with me!
Everyone, come on out!
Happy Birthday!
Happy Birthday, Reine!
It's like we're in Indonesia!
We are in Indonesia!
I'm ready for a vacation, ladies.
Finally, an Indonesian vacation!
Anyways, we have Calliope!
Oh hi, guys! Minna-san, it's me Mori Calliope from Hololive English -Myth-!
Oh hi, guys! Everyone, it's me Mori Calliope from Hololive English -Myth-!
What's going on? Hanmetsuba koko desu desu. Let's have fun together! Yatta!
What's going on? Hanmetsuba is here. Let's have fun together! Yay!
Yatta! We have Takanashi Kiara!
Yay! We have Takanashi Kiara!
Yes! Kiki-riki! I am also from Hololive English -Myth-!
Yes! Cock-a-doodle-doo! I am also from Hololive English -Myth-!
I am Takanashi Kiara, and finally, finally I made it to Indonesia again!
My second time!
And we have Zeta!
Finally, I'm back in Indonesia!
A cute cat! Oh, what a cute cat!
Did you bring some Churu?
No!
She hates that.
Is this your new cat? My new house cat, do you like her?
Oh, so cute!
For this year's birthday, I've put together lots of fun activities!
So I went on location shoots in both Indonesia and Japan!
And I'm also playing games that are popular in Indonesia with these wonderful guests!
And guess what? I'll be performing a brand-new song at the end of the stream!
So don't miss it, and stay until the very end!
Don't leave! Listen to her or else... The Peacock is talking, listen to her!
So first, let's take a look at the video from my location shoot in Indonesia!
Let's go!
Attention please! I'm Pavolia Reine, reporting from BSD City, Indonesia!
I've talked a lot about spicy food in Indonesia, but today, I will be introducing a wider variety of Indonesian food for everyone to get to know it even better!
Can anybody guess what we'll be eating today?
Here we are at Jalarasa The Breeze, BSD!
Embark on a culinary journey through the enchanting flavors of Indonesia at Jalarasa Indonesian Cuisine.
We are proud to bring you the authentic tastes of this archipelago nation.
Join us celebrate Indonesia's culinary tapestry!
First, we have perkedel jagung.
First, we have corn fritters.
Perkedel jagung are sweet corn fritters served with sambal roa. Mmm, you know how much I talk about this sambal!
Indonesia has a wide variety of sambal from different regions.
Sambal roa is a Manado specialty, and it is mainly made from chili and smoked ballyhoo fish.
Mari kita coba.
Let's try it.
Enak... Yummy!
Delicious... Yummy!
Next, we're gonna take some Tahu Lada Garam!
Next, we're gonna take some Salt and Pepper Tofu!
Salt and pepper tofu, yummy!
It's salt-pepper fried tofu complete with Indonesian aromatics.
Let's have a taste!
Hmm, this is like buttery flavor. I like it so much!
And this one is a Sundanese specialty called Karedok!
It's a traditional salad that uses a rich peanut sauce.
It has green eggplants, cucumbers, lemon basil, long beans, as well as bean sprouts.
So fresh!
Seger banget.
So fresh.
Next up, we're gonna go eat some fish!
This is also my first time eating this fish or even looking at this fish.
Did you guys know that a fish called Kudu-Kudu existed?
This is Kudu-Kudu Telur Asin.
This is Salted Egg Kudu-Kudu Fish.
Ini...
This...
So like Indonesia really has such a rich cultural cuisine. I've never eaten this before.
This is one of Djiwa Rasa specialties.
Even the skin's so tough.
So this is boxfish, apparently. This boxfish is served with a very popular 'telor asin' sauce.
The texture is membal-membal, you know. Enak banget!
The texture is chewy/bouncy, you know. It's so delicious!
I would recommend you guys eat this deh.
I would recommend you guys eat this.
Iya, I get what they're saying. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I get what they're saying. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, it tastes a little bit like chicken, it's so unique!
You guys definitely need to try it. Even like Indo bros, you guys got to go and try this.
Okay, so this is Iga Sapi Bakar Cabe Ijo.
It's a Javanese specialty, smoked ribs served with sambal ijo, a.k.a. green chili.
So, unlike the previous sambal we had, this one is made of only green chilis and other aromatics.
So the iga itself is sweet, so combined with the spicy and a little bit savory sambel ijo condiment, it makes for a really good dish.
So the rib itself is sweet, so combined with the spicy and a little bit savory green chili condiment, it makes for a really good dish.
Eh, dagingnya empuk juga. The meat is so soft, I recommend this one.
Hey, the meat is tender too. The meat is so soft, I recommend this one.
And this one's a classic, you know what it is, it's the beloved Nasi Goreng!!
So, we have this traditional chicken nasi goreng that's cooked with terasi, yeah guys.
So, we have this traditional chicken nasi goreng that's cooked with shrimp paste, yeah guys.
Terasi is a local shrimp or krill paste.
Smells so good.
I think it's known as belacan in Malaysia and kapi in Thailand, yeah.
Let's try this.
It's a mix of sweet and spicy and savory.
And as usual when you're eating Nasi Goreng, don't forget the kerupuk!
And as usual when you're eating Nasi Goreng, don't forget the crackers!
This is Nasi Liwet.
Nasi Liwet is a Sundanese specialty rice that is topped with salted fish, fried shallots, and more salted fish!
You can taste the depth of flavors. Enak banget, sumpah ini enggak bohong! No lie lie, this is so good!
You can taste the depth of flavors. It's so good, I swear no lie! No lie lie, this is so good!
And this is a Jakarta specialty, Kangkung Hotplate! Siapa yang suka makan kangkung di sini?
And this is a Jakarta specialty, Kangkung Hotplate! Who likes eating water spinach here?
So this morning glory is cooked with oyster sauce, topped with quail eggs and shrimp.
Look at the shrimp! There's also shrimp and seafood.
And this is Coto Makassar.
A Makassar specialty beef soup flavored with cloves and braised peanuts.
The history of Coto Makassar dates back to the 16th century, during the era of the Gowa Kingdom.
Coto was a special dish that symbolized wealth and luxury, as it was said to be served only to kings and nobles. Like me!!
Let's give it a taste.
Yummy! Cloves tuh itu lho guys, cengkeh, cengkeh.
Yummy! 'Cloves' are cloves, guys.
So fresh, menyegarkan.
So fresh, refreshing.
Now that we finished eating all the savory food, was really really good, now it's time to close it with a dessert!
Now that we finished eating all the savory food, which was really, really good, now it's time to close it with a dessert!
This time we have Es Pisang Ijo.
Es Pisang Ijo literally means iced green bananas. As you can see, look at these beautiful green bananas!
The bananas are wrapped in a green flour dough, and is served with coconut milk and pandan.
Let's give it a try!
Look at this. It also has sweet coconut rice pudding...
...Indonesian tapioca pearls with a beautiful pink color, condensed milk, and a special Ambon banana syrup.
I really really like their coconut rice pudding, tastes so good.
There's a little bit of savory complementing the sweetness.
Wow, that was a crazy meal! I can't believe the different flavor profile of every dish!
From the jagung perkedel up until the dessert...
From the corn fritters up until the dessert...
The portions are really big, so if you guys come here, I recommend you to come with your friends and share.
That's why, everybody, come visit Indonesia!!
But in case some of you are curious,
but aren't ready to come to Indonesia...
well, stay tuned for the next part coming up!
Hey! It's Reine back in the studio!
Did everyone enjoy our shoot in Indonesia?
The food was so delicious!
I really wish one day if you guys could go to Indonesia, please have a try!
All right, next up, we're gonna play our first game! Yay!
Shh... We have two games planned for today!
So let's move our bodies and have a blast together!
All right, let's get started. Our first game is...
...this!
Sorry... Sorry, there's a bit of distraction going on over here.
Oh god, feral feral animal over here!
Feral animal!
Guys, did you even notice this right here?
Gather around, gather around, gather around!
What is that? Apa sih?
What is that? What is it?
What's that thing, Reine? You gotta tell us what it is.
I've never seen anything like that in my life.
Looks delicious though, right?
Totally don't know what that is.
Is it like senbei?
Is it like rice crackers?
Kind of, yeah.
Is it a rice cake or something? -Tofu, tofu! -Tofu?!
Okay, okay, okay, well, we'll explain.
So this one will be an individual competition.
It is not a team battle,
and everyone will be competing against each other. Got it?
Yay, competition! Okay.
So this one will be called the Royal Kerupuk Contest!
Kerupuk Contest!
Yeah, crunchy-crunchy!
Oh, what exactly is it? Is it like a food?
It's so pretty though for being a food.
Yeah, so if you see, the start line is over there,
and then, the line on this side is the turnaround line.
So you go like chu-chu-chu-chu-chu and then...
And then, when the signal is given, begin at the starting line, and you have to do 5 squats!
Five?!
I did five squats yesterday!
No, no, no, listen, listen, listen...
The good thing is that there is no punishment game, okay? 'Cause this is the punishment!
And then after you do 5 squats, you go run towards here,
and without using your hands, you jump and you just like grab it with your mouth, and...
After five squats?
And then, you can finish it with your hands, yeah.
And then when you're done, just be like, "Hey, I'm done!" And then you run here,
and then...
...you just shake your butt 10 times! I'll be watching!
Why 10? -Yeah, 10. Or you want 20? -No, no, no, no. 10 is good.
20 just for Mori Calliope! -No, 10 is perfect.
All right, so like you do 10, and then once we count and give the okay, you run back...
...and then straight to the back, you know, the finish line, and then...
...yeah, the fastest one this round wins, I guess.
Okay! Yay!
Is this like an Indonesian game?
Yeah, pretty much. It's a kerupuk eating contest, but I don't think you shake your butt...
We got to spice it up! -It's Reine's original move, okay.
It's an upgraded version! -Sure, sounds good to me.
Okay, well, there's a bit of a height difference, but it should be fine.
Oh yeah, I mean we're all pretty tall except... -Except me?!
We can measure our height! -This is kind of unfair.
She just has to jump high. Cats can jump really high normally!
I'm not a cat! -You are!
Secret agents are really good at jumping really high, okay? -Okay, I'll jump.
Well, I guess so, looking at our heights, I guess me and Calli can go first?
Okay, okay!
So Kiara and Zeta, you will be judging our hip shaking, so you can stand...
I feel like Kiara is going to definitely give you more points though,
'cause I feel like she definitely wants to see that! She wants to see you like throwing it back!
I want to see you! I can be pretty strict when it comes to butt-shaking!
Maybe 'cause she wants to see more, she'll make you do twice as many! -Nah, nah, nah!
Got to be fair! 20 for Mori Calliope? -No thank you! 10 is a perfect number.
I definitely need to say it.
20 for Mori Calliope. -Oh, sure! Yeah, why not? -Oh, come on!
Okay, Kiara and Zeta, please give us the start signal, okay?
Okay!
Should we say it in Indonesian?
Tiga, dua, satu...
Three, two, one...
Okay, I'm ready.
Tiga! Dua! Satu! Go!
Three! Two! One! Go!
2, 3, 4, 5!
Nice squats! Go, go, go! Jump! Jump!
Oh, she got it!
So fast! It's so fast! I know, so crunchy!
Oh my god, it's going...
Very crunchy.
Speed eating contest!
They can't even talk right now.
Mogu mogu mogu mogu...
Munch munch munch munch...
Don't choke! Don't choke!
Yeah, don't choke!
Breathe, breathe!
Don't choke! Exhale! Inhale!
I think they're inhaling the food.
Okay, they both look pretty much done.
I know! Oh yeah! They're almost done! The last chewing!
And... yeah, you got it!
Okay, shake that booty!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5!
You think you're on 10? Count now!
It's 10!
Eh? Did they finish at the same time? Photo finish!
It seems like a tie.
Hey, quit shaking that ass!
I actually think that I gave you 15, by the way.
No, keep shaking! Keep shaking that ass!
Yabai.
Oh dear.
That seemed like a tie.
Good job, good job, though.
It was pretty much a photo finish, but maybe we can check who made it to the finish line first?
Yeah!
Just like my Umas.
Do you two have an idea who made it first?
I don't know. I feel like it was pretty much the exact same.
We just can't be sure.
You were pretty synced up with the mogu mogu also.
You were pretty synced up with the munching as well.
That surprised me. I didn't know that it was that hard to eat.
It was really dry! Yeah, it was really dry! I didn't know that!
Reine, have you ever eaten kerupuk so fast?
No, like, usually we eat it with drinks...
...and other food.
There's no water.
I got crumbs all over your beautiful tile. I'm sorry.
Oh, yeah! It's okay.
No need to clean, cuz next we're going, right? Yeah, everywhere!
But for now... I guess we shall give the point to...
Ah! We got it! We got it! A tie! A tie!
Okay, let's announce the time. Please announce the time for us.
Okay, we got the results!
So, Mori Calliope finished with a time of 55.1 seconds!
Yeah!
Not yet, not yet!
And Reine, it was a close one... finished with a time of 55.5 seconds!
Yay!
That's 0.4 seconds!
0.4! That was really close!
That was a great fight!
Good game, good game!
Rough!
Now we can take it a bit easy.
Maybe we'll need a drink after this.
Let me get a drink.
Is it our turn?
Oh yes! While we take a break...
...now you guys get to eat the super dry snack.
Yay! Good luck!
Yass! Yass! And shake around!
Yeah! That's the part that Kiara's most excited about.
If I ever get to it!
Okay, let's get into position.
Okay. Yes. Okay, sounds good.
See ya later. Here we go!
Bird versus Cat!
Yay!
Wait, which one's the bird and which one's the cat?
I'm the bird.
Huh? Oh, okay!
She really just doesn't want to be a cat.
Yeah, anything but!
But it's okay, less discussion, more ass shaking! Here we go!
Okay, how do we count in Indonesian?
Tiga... tiga, dua, dua, satu...
Three... three, two, two, one...
Satu! Go!
One! Go!
Go! Not yet, not yet!
No, no, no, not yet!
Oh! Get back there! No cheating!
No cheating! Remember to squat five times!
Ah, five times, okay.
And they need to be good squats!
Good squats, okay. Tiga, dua, satu...
Good squats, okay. Three, two, one...
Okay, gotcha. Here we go!
Tiga...
Three...
...dua...
...two...
...satu...
...one...
...Go!
1, 2...
...3...
...4, 5!
5! Nice! Woomph! Come on!
Oh, dang! She really went for it!
All right, get... Technique!
Oh my lord, Kiara is having a hard time! Back up, back up!
Kiara!
You got it, Kiara! You got to try again, you got to try again!
You're eating nothing! You're eating nothing! Gambatte!
You're eating nothing! You're eating nothing! Do your best!
Jump, jump, jump! You can just jump! Just jump!
Jump! Jump!
Try again! Try again! Go higher, go higher!
You got it! Eat! Eat, eat, eat! Come on! Down, down! You got this!
Yum, yum! Yummy! Pretend it's a delicious macaron!
Oh my god, are you okay?
Mmm, delicious macaron!
Use the saliva! Just generate some saliva, you got this!
Macarons, yummy, so sugary, sweet, delicious macarons.
It's like, what's her favorite sweet...
Done!
I ate it as fast as I could!
Kiara, you got this! Come on!
You're doing so good!
Good job, good job!
How many times? 10 times, 10 times.
I got it, I got it!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10!
Look at her shaking that ass!
Aw, look at those slowpokes over here!
I heard that line somewhere before. I heard that line too.
This book got you hypnotized.
My favorite clock says that!
Good job! Good job!
Your eating may have been better, but my ass shaking may have been better!
It was pretty good, it was pretty good!
It looked like a full-on meal.
That thing was going crazy! She was doing circles with it.
I wonder who won! Yeah, okay, let's announce...
Both of your times too. Okay, let me go center, center.
All right, let's hear the times, let me hear the times.
Where's the time? We need a time.
They're cooking! They're cooking up the time. They'll figure it out.
Stream, figure it out, by Pavolia Reine!
Yes, definitely don't miss it.
Damn, I jumped as high as I could, but... You were really going crazy!
You were doing it with enthusiasm! You're flying, like a superhero.
Thank you, thank you. I tried hard.
But Zeta, the short cats, she just... Cats jump really high!
Oh, we got the time! Oh, right!
3... Oh boy, okay.
And that's please...
Wait, what? Really? Can you announce it?
Are we sure this is correct? That's crazy!
Kiara finished with a time of 1 minute and 42 seconds!
Pretty good! It is good!
And it looks like Zeta finished with a time of 1 minute 40 seconds!
Oh, 2 seconds!
Congratulations!
That's crazy!
So? In total? Well, in total...
So after the first game...
...with 55.1, was it? I think 1. 55.1...
Callie! Callie has the fastest time!
Callie wins!
I did it!
Kiara was so extra though with her...
Thank you! I get extra points! That was pretty good though!
You were doing circles with it, it was nuts!
Look at that, she's shaking it fast!
You can't get that for free! You missed it, you're not gonna get it!
You can't get that for free!
Not for free! Whoa, whoa!
Maybe you can get it for free!
Sorry, Reine, sorry, stream.
No, it's fine. We'll clip that and upload a separate video of that.
Anyways, I'm so glad it worked out because I really wanted you guys to try the kerupuk.
I'm sorry it was like dry and stuff.
No, no, no! There are drinks over there, probably!
It was fun, right? Very fun!
It feels like I grew up in Indonesia now!
Yay! Right? Indonesian now! Yeah, it feels like I grew up in Indonesia too!
It feels like I grew up in Indonesia too!
Thanks for sharing that part of your childhood with us!
Okay, I guess it's time to move on to the next game, maybe?
I'm so game! Oh, there's more games? Yeah, but before that...
Before we continue, I would like everyone to watch a little bit of the footage...
...from my Japan location shoot! Getting more food!
So, here we go!
Let's go! Yay!
Hey, so did anyone get jealous watching me enjoy my delicious meal in Indonesia earlier?
Well, don't worry! 'Cause you can eat ID food right here in Tokyo too!
I'm at an Indonesian restaurant in Roppongi, Tokyo today.
The restaurant is called Wayang Bali,
and it's a lovely place where you can enjoy a wide variety of delicious Indonesian cuisine.
But I want to share my food with someone.
So, let's introduce these dishes to a very special JP member!
Yay! Haachama-chama! Worldwide-traveling idol, Akai Haato!
Yay!
Thank you so much Haachama for coming! -Thank you, too!
Let's head inside and see what delicious dishes they have today!
Yay, let's go! I'm so excited!
Into the restaurant
[Title: Into the restaurant]
I'm hungry! -I'm hungry too~ I'm excited!
So I have invited you out to eat with me to celebrate my birthday this year! -Happy Birthday! Thank you so much for coming!
So like for this year I wanted to try something new and celebrate my... Indonesian culture by sharing it with everyone!
We ate instant noodles together before, right? -Right!
So that's why I wanted you to try some real Indonesian food this time!
So you can level up your Indonesian! -Indonesian! Next time I go to Indonesia! -Yes!
There are also like spicy food here, but I think they won't be as spicy as the spicy noodles, so you don't have to worry!
But you're excited about spicy, right? -Mmm!
I want spicy! Spicy! Pedam, pedam...
Pedas! -Pedas! Pedas! Yay!
Haachama, PEDAS LOVER! -Pedas lover! I love pedas! -Me too, I love pedas.
How do you say "I love pedas" in Indonesian? -Oh... Aku...
suka... -Aku suka... -pedas. -Aku suka pedas!
Yeah, that means "I love spicy". -Aku suka pedas! Yay!
See? I'm slowly turning Haachama Indonesian by feeding her Indonesian food! -Yay!
Oh~ so this is the menu!
Oh, it's also written here: "Indonesian Food Vocabulary". So if you wanna learn Indonesian, there's so many words here!
Karai, pedas. -Pedas! Yeah, I love pedas! -Haachama pedas suki desho~ Yeah!
Spicy is pedas. -Pedas! Yeah, I love pedas! -Haachama likes pedas, right? Yeah!
Kore wa... ada kukus, bakar! -Bakar! -Bakar! Bakar!
This is... there's kukus, bakar! -Bakar! -Bakar! Bakar!
R~! -R ga tsuite iru yo. Bakar is yaku! -Yaku.
R~! -There's an 'R' sound. Bakar means to grill! -To grill.
Yes. Itameru wa... tumis. -Tumis! -Yeah!
Yes. To stir-fry is... tumis. -Tumis! -Yeah!
Indonesian already! Indonesian school starts now!
Satay~ -Do you know satay? -Ah, yaki, kushiyaki! Kushiyaki! -Yes! Indonesian no kushiyaki desu ne.
Satay~ -Do you know satay? -Ah, grilled, grilled skewers! Grilled skewers! -Yes! It's Indonesian grilled skewers.
Do you know what tempe is? -Tempe? Tempe? Tempe? I don't know.
So, tempe is like... what is it? In Indonesia, it's kind of like the primary source of protein! -Protein?! -Yes! -Wow!
And then, I think they kind of use the same base materials as natto! -Natto?! -Yeah! So they're like cousins! -A cousin! -A mix, yeah!
Protein natto! -Yeah! Do you like natto? -Ah, I like natto! -Oh, really?
Can you eat it? -I've tried, but I don't know if I like it.
Ah, how to... how to like natto? -Maze-maze! Maze-maze! -Maze-maze. Okay, okay. Mix!
Ah, how to... how to like natto? -Mix-mix! Mix-mix! -Mix-mix. Okay, okay. Mix!
So if you like natto, then maybe you will like tempe! -Oh, yeah! Tempe!
There's also... this is also spicy, dabu-dabu. -Dabu-dabu! I like the name! -Dabu-dabu is the sauce name, and there's also spicy chicken, ayam pedas.
Well, anyway! We went through a lot of the menu, so I guess we should order a bunch and we can try them all!
While we wait for our food... But we should also give you... since you're turning Indonesian, we need to give you an Indonesian introduction. -Oh, yeah! How to do that?
So can you say your introduction just in your normal...? -Haachama-chama~! Worldwide-traveling idol, Akai Haato!
So in Indonesian, that would be...
Haachama-chama! Idola... yang... menjelajahi... dunia... Akai Haato!
Menjelajahi dunia Akai Haato... What was the first word? -Idola... -Idola yang menjelajahi... -dunia... -dunia! Idola yang menjelajahi...
Idola yang menjelajahi dunia!
The world-exploring idol...
Akai Haato!
料理の準備ができたみたい！
Oh, it looks like our food is on the way!
お腹も空いてるし
I'm starting to get hungry.
さっそく食べましょう〜！
Let's eat!
Okay, our first dish has arrived. This is tempe!
Okay, our first dish has arrived. This is tempeh!
Are you hungry?
I'm hungry!
こちらがテンペのソースだよ
And this is the sauce that they give...
Dipして食べようね
...yeah, so we can dip and eat it.
このソースは甘いの？
Is this sauce sweet?
甘いのかな？辛いのかな？
Mmm, I wonder... Is it sweet or spicy?
お箸とスプーンが手元にあるんだけど
We have chopsticks and spoons here...
スタッフが手で食べてもいいって言うから手で食べるね
...but staff said we can eat with our hands, so I'll eat with my hands.
まずはソースなしで食べているよ
So first, I'll try without the sauce.
私も食べてみるね ソースにつけよう
I'll try dipping it in the sauce.
ソースは甘さのある味だね
The sauce has a sweet flavor, right?
これも試していい？
Can I try this one too?
辛いソースだね！
It's a spicy sauce!
別に用意してもらったソースなんだけど多分結構辛いよ
They prepared a separate sauce for us, but it's probably pretty spicy.
さっそく食べてみよう
Let's try it right away!
Gimana, Haachama?
How is it, Haachama?
お箸で救出しよう
Let me rescue it with chopsticks.
We can rescue it with chopsticks.
It's spicy!
I like it!
普通のソースより辛っ
Spicier than the regular sauce!
辛さが伝わったでしょ(笑)
You can tell how spicy it is, right? (Laughs)
どっちのソースが好きだった？
Which sauce did you like better?
辛い方！
The spicy one!
はあちゃまは辛いのが好きだね〜
Haachama loves spicy food, huh~
The next one we have Tahu Isi.
Next, we have Tahu Isi.
Tahu Isi.
豆腐を揚げてあるんだよ
They fried the tofu...
すごくクリスピーだよ！
It's super crispy!
Oh, it sounds good.
この豆腐を開いてみるとね…
If you open up this tofu...
の中に詰めてあるんだね
See, it's stuffed inside.
もやしやにんじんなどの野菜が詰めてあるから
It's stuffed with vegetables like bean sprouts and carrots...
ぜひ食べてみて〜
...so definitely try it!
半分こする？
Want to split it in half?
この辛いソースとすごく合うと思うよ
I think it goes really well with this spicy sauce.
Spicy... Spicy...
はあちゃまもインドネシアスタイルで手で食べてるね
Look, Haachama is also eating Indonesian style with her hands.
もちもち
Oh, it's chewy, a little bit.
このソース思ってたよりだいぶ辛いよ
This sauce is way spicier than I thought.
The more you eat, the spicier it gets!
Yeah, exactly!!!
結構辛いな〜と思って食べているとどんどん辛さが広がってくる
You eat thinking it's pretty spicy, and the spiciness just keeps spreading.
インドネシアに行けばどこでも見かけるんだけど
You can see this anywhere if you go to Indonesia...
例えば屋台とか
...like at food stalls...
屋台や道路端で気軽に買えるインドネシアで親しまれているストリートフードだよ
It's a popular street food in Indonesia that you can easily buy at stalls or on the roadside.
屋台に行ってみたいな〜
I want to go to a street stall~
Yeah~
Okay, next!
Next one!
This is called Ayam Sisit.
Ayam Sisit.
茹でたり揚げたりした鶏肉を細かく裂いて香り豊かなスパイスで味付けした料理ね
It's a dish of shredded boiled or fried chicken seasoned with rich, aromatic spices.
細かくほぐしてあるから味がよく染み込んでいて
It's shredded finely so the flavor soaks in really well.
Bumbu Genepというペーストが使われているの
It uses a paste called Bumbu Genep.
多分さっきのソースほど辛くはないはず
It's probably not as spicy as the previous sauce.
きっと大丈夫
It should be fine.
普段はライスと一緒に食べる料理なんだけどおそらくライスを一緒に出されていない理由は
Normally this dish is eaten with rice, but the reason it wasn't served with rice...
まだまだこれから料理が出てくるから
...is because there are still more dishes coming.
ひとまずいただきましょう
For now, let me eat!
辛くはないよね？
It's not spicy, right?
種類までは分からないけどアロマティックスパイスが効いてる
I don't know the exact ingredients, but the aromatic spices are really effective.
あれに似てる！
Ah, it's like that!
イカ！
Squid!
干しイカ！
Dried squid!
さきイカならぬさきチキンだね
It's like dried chicken instead of dried squid.
すごく合いそう…
It seems like it would go so well...
お酒と相性がすごく良さそう
It seems like it would go great with alcohol!
ビールと一緒にね
Together with beer!
おつまみに良さそうだね
It seems great as a snack to go with drinks!
Ooh, and now the main dishes are out!
This is Ayam Sambal Matah!
Ayam Sambal Matah.
Ayamが鶏肉のことで
Ayam means chicken...
Sambal Matah生調味料のことだよ
...and Sambal Matah is a raw condiment dish.
サンバ？！
Samba?!
踊りの？
The dance?
SambaじゃなくてSambalね
It's Sambal, not Samba.
辛い調味料だよ
It's a spicy seasoning.
生の素材を細かく刻んでいて
Fresh, raw ingredients are finely chopped,
酸味と辛味を生かしつつ
creating a sour and spicy flavor,
熱いオイルをかけて仕上げるの
and topped off with hot oil.
これはお肉だよね？
Is this meat?
鶏肉だよ
It's chicken meat.
食べたことがある味がする！
I've tasted this before!
インドネシアの麺料理かな
Like Indonesian noodles!
言われてみれば似ているものがあるね
Now that you mention it, there is a similar flavor.
私の好物の軟骨だよ
This is cartilage, my favorite!
もっと食レポに集中しなきゃなんだろうけど
We're supposed to give a food review,
美味しすぎて食べることしかできない
but it's so good, all I can do is eat!
しょうがないよね
Can't be helped, right?
私も軟骨を食べてみよっと
I'll try the cartilage too!
軟骨はどこかな？
Where is the cartilage?
Sambalに使われているオニオン食べてみる？
Want to try the onions in the Sambal?
生だけじゃなくオニオンフライもあるよ
There are fried onions in addition to fresh ones.
ミーゴレンみたいな味がする
It tastes like Mie Goreng!
確かに酸味を感じられるね
You can definitely taste the sourness.
辛さはあんまりないね
It's not really spicy.
辛味というより塩味があるよね
Rather than spicy, it's more salty.
インドネシアには色んな種類のSambalがあって
Indonesia has many types of Sambal,
これとはまた違う種類もあるから
including ones different from this,
機会があれば他の種類も試してほしいな
so I hope you try other kinds if you get the chance.
そろそろ辛いのが食べたいでしょ
You want to eat something spicy by now, right?
早く食べたいから食べていい？
Can I go ahead and eat this now?
これがピーナッツソースなんだけど
This is peanut sauce,
すっごく美味しいんだよ
and it's super delicious!
鶏肉をピーナッツソースで食べたことないや
I've never eaten chicken with peanut sauce before.
今日は鶏肉をたくさん食べてるね！
We're eating a lot of chicken today!
インドネシア料理は鶏肉をよく使うよね
Chicken is used a lot in Indonesian cuisine, right?
すごくクリーミーだね
It's super creamy.
ピーナッツソース以外でも甘い醤油を使うこともあるんだよ
Besides peanut sauce, they sometimes use sweet soy sauce too.
同じ鶏肉でも味付けが全然違うよね
Even with the same chicken, the flavor is completely different.
調味料でかなり変わるよね
The seasonings really change it, don't they?
次はどれを食べたい？
Which one do you want to try next?
日常的によく食べられるのは鶏肉だけど
Chicken is what people usually eat the most,
牛肉やラム肉は珍しいけど美味しいよね
but beef and lamb are also delicious even if they're uncommon.
ビーフすっごく美味しいね！
The beef is super delicious!
エビ好きだよ〜
I love shrimp~
尻尾も食べる？
Do you eat the tail too?
多分？どうだろう？
Maybe? Who knows?
エビはエビだけどなんか違う
It's shrimp, but different from usual shrimp.
味付けが通常のSateと違って
The seasoning is different from regular Sate,
ピーナッツソースとかの定番じゃないけどすごく美味しい
it's not the usual peanut sauce, but it's really delicious!
バイバイ オニオーン
Bye-bye, onion!
ラムもピーナッツソースじゃないんだね
The lamb doesn't use peanut sauce either, huh?
なんの味だろう？
I wonder what flavor this is?
甘味が強い感じのソースだね
It's a sauce with a strong sweet note.
レッツゴースパイシー
Let's go spicy!
水飲むからちょっと待って
Hold on, I need a drink of water.
甘辛い感じかな…
It's kind of sweet and spicy...
あ、後から辛さがくるやつだ
Ah, it's the type where the spiciness kicks in later.
本当だ！じわじわ辛さがくる
You're right! The spiciness slowly builds up.
美味しくて好きだけどね
But it's delicious and I like it.
あ〜辛い
Ah~ it's spicy!
どの調味料か分からないけどすごく美味しい
I don't know what seasoning this is, but it's super delicious.
5種類のうちどれが1番好きだった？
Out of the five kinds, which one was your favorite?
エビのやつが好き！
I like the shrimp one!
私は牛肉のSateが1番気に入ったかな
I think I liked the beef Sate the best.
これまであまり牛肉のSateを食べたことがなかったからだと思うけど
Probably because I hadn't eaten beef Sate very often before.
これまで あまり牛肉のSateを 食べたことがなかったからだと思うけど
I hadn't really eaten beef satay much before, but...
すっごくおいしかった！
It was super delicious!
まだ料理があるよ！
We have more food!
かなり量の料理があるから ライスをもらえなかったのかな
Maybe that's why they didn't give us rice since there's so much food.
さっきの鶏肉のSateがまだ辛い！
The chicken satay from earlier is still spicy!
これは辛くないから大丈夫だよ
This one isn't spicy, so it's okay.
ミーゴレンだよ！
This is Mi Goreng!
前にインスタントのミーゴレンを食べたでしょ？
You ate instant Mi Goreng before, right?
これは本格的なやつだよ
This is the real, non-instant version.
これが辛くなくてよかった...
I'm so glad this isn't spicy...
辛い食べ物は大好きだけど
I love spicy food, but...
ちょっと休憩したかったから
I wanted a bit of a break.
もちもちしてる！
It's nice and chewy!
太麺だね！
And they're thick noodles!
麺の食感がなんていうか...
The texture of the noodles is, how should I say...
アニョアニョ
Very "enyal-enyal".
アニョアニョ？
"Enyal-enyal"?
インドネシア語でもちもちっていう意味だよ
It's Indonesian for "chewy"!
可愛い！
Ah, it's cute!
あにょあにょだよ～
It's "anyo-anyo"~
各家庭でミーゴレンの味があるんだけど ここのミーゴレンすごく好きだな
Every household has its own Mi Goreng flavor, but I really like this style.
焼きそばと似てるよね
It's like yakisoba, right?
インドネシアの焼きそばだね
It's Indonesian yakisoba.
甘めの焼きそばって感じ
It feels like a sweeter version of yakisoba.
最初に納豆のいとこを食べて
First we had natto's cousin,
今は焼きそばのいとこを食べてるね
and now we're eating yakisoba's cousin.
最後に、これは「ラワール」というバリ島の伝統料理だよ
And finally, this is a traditional Balinese dish called Lawar.
私も食べたことがなかったんだよね
I'd actually never eaten this before either.
今日が初めてだからすごく楽しみ！
Today is my first time, so I'm really looking forward to it!
まずピーナッツがあるでしょ
First, there are peanuts, right?
これピーナッツか！
Oh, these are peanuts!
納豆かと思ってた！違ったや
I thought it was natto! Turns out it wasn't.
そしてインゲンね
And then string beans.
インゲンは英語で何ていうのかな？
How do you say "ingen" in English?
豚肉が使われることが多いんだけど
Usually, pork is used in this,
ハラール仕様で鶏肉が使われているね
but because this is a halal version, they used chicken instead.
どんな味がするのか楽しみ！食べてみよう！
I wonder what it tastes like, so excited! Let me try it!
インゲンから食べてみるね
I'll try the string beans first.
インゲンがサクサクしていていいね
The string beans are nice and crunchy.
スナックみたいだね
It's like a snack!
確かにスナック菓子っぽいね
Yeah, it really is like a snack.
塩味も効いてる おやつにつまみたい！
It's nice and salty! I'd love to eat this as a snack!
美味しい！
It's delicious!
めっちゃいっぱい食べたね！
We ate so much food!
おなかは大丈夫？
Is your stomach doing okay?
ちゃんと別腹は空いてる？
Do you still have room in your dessert stomach?
デザートも入るよね？
You can still eat dessert, right?
デザートの時間だよ！！！
It's time for dessert!!!
マンゴープリンだよ！
It's mango pudding!
この下にあるのはチョコかな？
Is that chocolate at the bottom?
砂糖か何かかな？
Or maybe sugar or something?
食べて確かめよう
Let's taste it to find out.
すごくやわらかいね
It's so soft!
すごくクリーミー！
It's so creamy!
確信はないけどこのクリーミーさは ココナッツミルクかな？
I'm not sure, but maybe this creaminess comes from coconut milk?
この下のブラウンのものは何？
What is this brown stuff at the bottom?
さっきからその部分が気になってるんだよね
I've been curious about that part for a while.
私にとらせてね
Let me get some for you.
キャラメル味だ
It tastes like caramel.
キャラメルソースだね！
It's caramel sauce!
もう１つデザートがあるみたいだよ
Looks like there's another dessert!
揚げバナナだよ！
It's fried bananas!
バナナにバターを付けたりして 衣をつけるんだよ
You coat the banana in batter and deep-fry it.
絶対に美味しいジャン
That has got to be delicious!
インドネシアでは定番のおやつだね
It's a classic snack in Indonesia.
アイスと一緒に食べることはあまりないけど ファンシーだから不満はないよ
We don't usually eat it with ice cream, but it's fancy so no complaints!
すごくいい匂いがするね
It smells so good!
※バナナが熱々です
*The banana is extremely hot!*
あ、熱っ！
Ow, hot!
熱い！
It's hot!
バターが染みていて美味しいね
I think the butter is soaked in and delicious.
It's the best!!!
甘さ控えてちょうどいい
It's sweet, but not too sweet.
アップルパイっぽい感じ
It feels like apple pie.
カメラロールが黙々と食べているだけの私たちの映像でいっぱいになってるよね
The camera roll is going to be full of videos of us just silently eating.
完食 / Finished
[Finished]
今日は来てくれて本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming today!
招待してくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for inviting me!
どうだった？ 楽しかったよ〜
How was it? - It was so fun~
私もしとっても楽しかったよ
I had so much fun too!
今日はたくさんのインドネシア料理を食べたけど
We ate a lot of Indonesian food today, but...
次は what do we do?
Next, what do we do?
もっとレベルを上げるために！
To level up even more!
インドネシアへ行くよ！
Let me go to Indonesia!
インドネシア料理が好きになったよ
I've come to love Indonesian food!
料理の次は実際にインドネシアへ行こう
After the food, let's actually go to Indonesia!
インドネシア料理を作るよ！
I'll make Indonesian food!
はあちゃまのインドネシア料理
Haachama's Indonesian cooking!
お願いがあるんだけど…
I have a favor to ask, though...
日本のローカルな食事を食べに連れて行って
Take me out to eat local Japanese food.
日本のみんなが普段どんなものを食べているのか知りたい
I want to know what everyone in Japan usually eats.
私が教えてあげるよ
I'll teach you!
日常的な食事を味わってみたい〜
I want to taste everyday meals~
Yummy
ということでみんな！ 今後もはあちゃまとレイネのアドベンチャーを楽しみにしててね！
So everyone, look forward to more of Haachama and Reine's adventures!
ということでスタジオへ戻しましょう
So with that, let's head back to the studio!
Studio Reine, are you there?
スタジオのレイネさ〜ん 取れますかぁ〜？
Reine-san in the studio, can you hear us~?
はい！スタジオのレイネです！
Yes! This is Reine in the studio!
So, what did you think of our trip to the Indonesian restaurant in Japan with Haachama?
Oh, that looks so delicious! I want to go!
I'll take you guys there next time. - Please! Food, food, food!
I'm getting hungry!
All right, next up, let's play our second game!
Yay! Okay!
Well, just like in game one, we will be competing to see who can reach the goal the fastest.
Yeah, okay. Are you guys ready?
No! For this game, we will be using this item!
Okay! Oh wow, a beach ball! Yay!
Man, I wish I was a baller, I wish I was a little bit taller, I wish I had a 6'4" Impala...
...or a girl who looked cute, I would call her.
Woah, the violence! I'm bullying the camera! This isn't soccer, all right? Knock that off.
The cup is over. - Okay, okay, okay!
The rules for the next game are super simple.
You hold this ball between your legs like you're giving birth!
Yeah, so like this...
And then, you guys will be racing while hopping!
Aw, I thought we were gonna play football. - No, you're not! Next time, next year, football.
Let's go, let's go! Football next year, let's go.
And the game is called the Bola Challenge!
Bola means ball. - Bola Challenge!
Bola, bola! Who got the biggest ball?
Mine's definitely small, just because of the skirt situation.
Oh, so that's why! Yeah, small ball. Hey, hey, stop.
ボールを足の間に挟んで跳び、スタートからゴールまでのタイムを競う
Hold the ball between your legs and hop from start to finish.
Start there, hop to the turnaround point, and make it to the finish line, right?
Simple, right? - Yeah, very simple!
Yeah, okay. Well, there's a twist, actually.
To make things more interesting, we're adding two extra rules.
ただし、レース中は「お題」に沿った会話をし続けてください
However, you must keep talking about the given topic throughout the race.
Oh! Yeah, so it's just like, you guys are good at yapping, right?
I guess so! - Yeah, now you can do that while...
While jumping? I never tried yapping while balling.
Never too late to pick up a new skill!
Put it on your resume.
And just like before, two people will compete at a time, so make sure you keep chatting with your opponent while you race.
All right, the yapping has... Woah, are you okay?
Are you okay? - I tried doing a trick, I failed!
Go on!
折り返し地点を過ぎたら、相手の邪魔をしてもOKです
After the turnaround, you're allowed to mess with your opponent!
So if you want to tickle your opponent... - Yeah, exactly!
Hey! I'm not gonna do that to you... - Yeah, basically like that.
I tried this during rehearsal,
well, I tried, and I guess it's got to be,
Well, I tried, and I guess it's gonna be...
you know, it's kind of tiring, so it's your choice basically.
You can just like focus on racing, or, you know, if you can,
you're a little bit mischievous, you want to tickle, you want to tickle your opponent.
you're a little bit mischievous, you want to tickle your opponent.
Yeah, you want to, yeah, you want to lift them up and kiss them, that's fine too.
Yeah, you want to lift them up and kiss them, that's fine too.
Are you ticklish? / I'm not ticklish.
I'm not...
Liar! I think she might be ticklish.
No, I'm not ticklish at all. Hiding something. / Wait, now use it to your advantage!
Never let your opponent know your weakness.
No, no, no, no.
But anyway, alright, everybody, let's get into position. Calli and Kiara?
Oh boy, I'm first again! / Yeah, that's fine.
Let's go. You're already getting started. Don't make it too hard for yourself.
Yeah, you make it harder for yourself.
Wait, what's our topic?
Wait, wait, wait, hold on, hold on. I'm gonna go here first. Ooh!
Can we talk?
Okay, your topic is...
Things I love about my cat!
Ah! Easy, right? Nekochima! / That's a pretty easy one!
You guys both have adorable cats at home, so go ahead and brag as much as you want!
Okay. Right?
Okay, that might actually help me forget that I'm tired.
Oh, yeah, cats take that all away.
So fluffy. What about... can we talk about that cat over there?
No!
Focus on your game! That's a secret agent disguised as a cat!
True, true, true. Or a cat disguised as a secret agent.
Are you guys ready?
Yeah, ready as I'll ever be.
All right. On your marks... 3, 2, 1, go!
Chutu is so fluffy and cute! She has the most adorable black stripe...
right down the back of her... What are you doing?!
Her tail is so fluffy and long! / No, no, no!
No, Calli!
Should we increase the distance?
Should we make it a little further? / Wait, do I have to finish it?
Well, tell me a little bit about your cats, Kiara. / That's all?
Currently, um, I'm not with my cats, so that makes me really sad.
But, um, my cat caretakers are sending me videos of them,
and they're sleeping like on the towels, even though I said, "Don't sleep on the towels."
Because the towels are not supposed to have cat hair all over.
But it's okay, I forgive them. I'll just buy new towels, so there's cat towels and human towels.
That's a good idea to separate them like that. / Oh, Calli!
That is so good!
Nice job! Good job!
That is so good! Oh my.
Well done, well done. I respect the legwork, that was intense.
I mean, this is... I actually do this during my training anyway.
Yeah, hold the ball between my legs and jump, so I kind of had an unfair advantage.
Oh, so you're... okay, you built up that skill.
Every muscle training session. / You trained the balling!
Okay, ultra!
Let's announce your times, girls!
Let me replay! Let's go, let's go, let's go! No, your turn! / Ganbatte, ganbatte!
Well, I wonder who won?
That was a close one! / It was a close match.
It was very, very close!
Okay, silence please. All right!
So...
It's close! Can you say my time first? / Okay, your time first, okay, okay, let's see.
Kiara, your time was 46.5 seconds!
Yay! That's crazy!
That's a crazy dance move! / Yeah!
That's crazy, crazy dance moves! She sure knows how to throw down!
And yours... / Okay, now Calli...
It was a close one. / Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Your time was 10.5 seconds!
(Laughs) Ooh!
I could have been a little faster, I guess. / Oh man.
This is me on slow days.
Good job, Kiara. / Yeah, I need to...
work on my feelings...
How are you feeling? / How are you feeling?
I had an unfair advantage... / I just wish I was a baller!
Well, first you gotta be a little bit taller.
By a 6'4 Impala. Then we'll talk.
Well, I hope that your match will be a little bit closer.
Ganbatte! Good match, Calli! / Mhm, okay. Yeah!
Ganbatte! / You guys are up! Ganba, ganba!
Take your ball! / Okay, sorry, my ball.
Get your ball! / So I left my ball...
Don't forget your balls! Get my ball... / Don't forget!
Oyaji... / Hey, can we make our balls meet?
What? Hi, nice to meet you. This is my ball. / Nice to meet you, ball.
Aw, well. Did we just meet? Yeah, we just met. Do your balls know each other?
Not yet, not yet!
After this race, we'll get to know each other now.
All righty. Well then, it looks like I'm going to be tanto for this match.
All righty. Well then, it looks like I'm going to be in charge of this match.
Ey-oh.
So, here is your topic, okay?
Compliment each other in Japanese!
No English, no Indonesian allowed. This is a good challenge for somebody or two people who speak three languages!
Also Kiara also speaks three languages.
So you'll have no excuse.
Compliment each other in German.
German?
Guten Morgen! Guten Morgen!
Good morning! Good morning!
Danke schön, danke schön, danke schön!
Thank you very much, thank you very much, thank you very much!
Okay, are you ready?
On your marks, get set, go!
背が高い！
You're tall!
髪が綺麗！
Your hair is pretty!
可愛い！
Cute!
脚が長い！
Long legs!
今度デート行こう！
Let me take you on a date sometime!
絶対絶対行こう！
Let me definitely take you out!
チュチュチュ！
Smooch smooch smooch!
頭が良い！
Smart!
Wait, wait, did they compliment each other?
Yeah, I think so, I'm pretty sure I heard some compliments.
It was a little hard to say to hear what they were saying, but they were definitely complimenting each other.
It was a little hard to hear what they were saying, but they were definitely complimenting each other.
What were you saying to each other?
Um, I was saying "se ga takai", "ashi ga nagai"...
Um, I was saying "you're tall", "long legs"...
...and then "your hair is pretty", and then "let's go on a date sometime"...
...and then I said "chu chu chu", I think that's...
...and then I said "smooch smooch smooch", I think that's...
Ah, those are compliments!
What did you say to her?
I said, "Wow, kimi wa subarashii!"
I said, "Wow, you are wonderful!"
"Atama mo ii!"
"You're smart too!"
Oh, atama mo ii! That's good!
Oh, smart too! That's good!
So teeteey!
So wholesome!
Yeah, those are compliments. That was successful then.
Good job, team. And we got the times ready.
Good job, let's check out the time. Yeah, let's see, let's see.
Good job. Let me check out the time. Yeah, let me see, let me see.
Well, do you both know each other now?
Yes, let me meet!
Yes, let us meet!
Let me meet! You guys are getting to know each other.
Let us meet! You guys are getting to know each other.
All righty, fine, fine.
Hey, I want my ball my ball should hang out with you guys too. Oh, wow.
Hey, I want my ball to hang out with you guys too. Oh, wow.
We only just met, but this is kind of fun. I don't know.
Do we have the times? Let's check them out.
We probably have them now. I think I could tell who won, though.
Got it. I saw it.
It was close! It was close!
It was definitely closer than ours.
Just like earlier, it was close.
Okay, we got it. The times, do you want to say them?
Short thing. Okey-dokey. Now, Reine, your time was...
Sure thing. Okey-dokey. Now, Reine, your time was...
12 seconds!
And Zeta... Zeta...
大丈夫？大丈夫。 The balls be wildin'.
Are you okay? Okay. The balls be wildin'.
Zeta, your time was 14 seconds.
Wow! Good job! Any number with a number four in it is a good number.
It is a good number, so...
The winner of your match was... Reine!
What a match! Yeah, yeah, yeah! Good job!
How do you feel? Yeah, I feel...
...great! Energized!
Well, that's good. Ready for more exercise?
Yeah!
This is rigged! She's the birthday girl! Of course she would win!
Everyone, you all did an amazing job. Oh, thank you.
We finished both games, so we're gonna total up everyone's times and announce the winner.
Yes, yes. Find someone with the shortest total time.
大丈夫？ Okay!
Are you okay? Okay!
It's hot here in Indonesia, so take...
Take a breath! Take a breath while I do...
CPR, CPR everyone!
Kiara, you do it! Do you do it! You do the CPR!
Kiara, you do it! You do it! You do the CPR!
I'm dying! Somebody CPR please!
Kiara's doing it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
やばい、やばい、大丈夫。事故、事故。
Oh no, oh no, are you okay? Accident, accident.
That's what she wanted! She lives!
Good job. I'm alive!
お疲れ！ I'm alive!
Good work! I'm alive!
お疲れ！ You're alive. Congrats on being alive.
Good work! You're alive. Congrats on being alive.
Do we have the results yet?
While we're waiting on the results, here's my sick trick.
Okay, Callie catch! Okay.
I'm ready. Are you ready to catch? Yeah.
Well, it was a little low.
It was a little low! All right, one more, one more.
Here you go. Three, two, one!
Whoa! Yeah!
Let's go Takamori! Takamori!
Takamori ball masters! Takamori ball masters! Takamori knows ball!
Wow, we ballin'! Good job.
That was awesome. That was a sick trick.
We should become like a football club.
A team.
Results are in! We got them!
The results are in, and let's announce the winner, okay?
And let me start with the 4th place. Drum roll, please!
And let me start with 4th place. Drum roll, please!
Takanashi Kiara!
4 is the best number!
Last place, but I mean, first place in...
Last place, but I mean, 1st place in...
in your hearts, right?
Yes! So true!
Fourth place is first from the bottom.
Oh, すごい! So true! I'm so すごい!
Oh, amazing! So true! I'm so amazing!
Also number one ball number.
Number one baller. You see how well she knows that ball?
Can I see it? Wow!
Okay, and then...
...the third place is our very own beloved house cat...
...Vestia Zeta!
Secret agent! Well, at least I'm third!
Okay, hand please. Hand please.
She got it. It's so cute.
Okay, good girl! Congratulations!
Give me paw. That's more of a dog thing though.
Yeah, well... Cats, dogs, same thing!
Not the same animal. Not the same animal.
They are kinda adjacent!
Okay, and in second place, just missing out on the win...
...it's...
...Pavolia Reine!
Good girl! I know her! Good girl!
Happy birthday!
Wait, Calli, you didn't confer the win on her birthday?
Oh, should I... Wait, what? Should I have done that?
Was that, like... a manners thing?
No, no, no, I prepared something for the winner, so that's okay.
And that means our champion...
...with the fastest time, Mr. Ball, Mori Calliope!
Yay!
Please don't hurt me! Ah! Ah, please don't hurt me!
Congratulations! Thank you! Thank you! Oh, my gosh!
I appreciate it. I have been training.
So, Mori, who got the fastest time, has earned a very special trophy!
Thank you!
Da-da-da-da-da-da! Oh, trophy! I have to entrust my ball to you.
This is a very special trophy for today!
Yay! Wow!
Thank you! Thank you so much! Thank you!
Anyways, any comments? Any, you know, interview, winner interview?
Ahem, this is really fun. I had such a great time enjoying Indonesia!
But more than anything, I'm glad we all got to have lots of fun...
...on your very special day, Reine. Thank you for inviting us.
And sharing with us some of the games that, you know, you used to like to play and stuff like that.
It was just a really good time. So, thank you.
No, thank you so much, Calli. And thank you, Kiara...
...and Zeta for participating!
And that's all for the games. Thank you so much for playing with me, everyone!
Yay! Thank you!
And coming up next in the stream, I have a very, very special surprise...
...a brand new song performance!
What?! New song, new song, new song!
But before we get there...
...I want to show you the teaser video for the new song and introduce some merch!
So don't go anywhere, and stay with us until the very end!
We will! Yay! All right, now...
...let's take a look at the teaser video for the new song!
Yay!
Pavolia Reine New Original Song - Endless Blue - 2026.09.09 24:00 RELEASE
How did you like the teaser video?
Yeah! Yeah!
What are they doing? You guys are so suspicious!
So, well, this new song is...
...you know my very first original song, Gate Open START!?
Yes! Yes!
So if Gate Open START! is the opening of an anime...
...this is kind of, you know, a little bit more mellow vibe, maybe like a second season opening of Gate Open START!
I love that! Yeah!
Reine Anime, when? Let's go!
I'd watch it! Second season, おめでとう! おめでとう!
I'd watch it! Second season, congratulations! Congratulations!
Well, as I mentioned earlier, I'll be performing it later, so please look forward to it!
Yay!
And now, before I perform the new song, I'd like to have my guests here, my beautiful, beautiful guests...
...help me introduce this year's birthday merch!
All right! All right! We won't let you down!
Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Get your wallets out right now!
Tada! Okay, first up...
..."Take me with U" Acrylic Diorama Stand!
Featuring a beautiful illustration by Enji-sensei...
...of me enjoying me—I am—with a beautiful view!
Whenever you go to a restaurant, please take me with you!
Yay!
What are you guys doing?
Get your oshi katsu pictures! Yeah! Don't forget oshi katsu!
Get your fan activity pictures! Yeah! Don't forget fan activity!
Next!
おいおい、キアラ！
Hey, hey, Kiara!
You have a part in this? -Yes! I have jobs to do!
I will introduce the second item. The travel towel!
Don't let the name fool you, this is a super versatile towel...
...that you can use not only for traveling, but also in your everyday life!
Wipe your armpits! Wipe your armpits!
It sure will come in handy at the next fest, too, for example!
Towel! Towel! Towel! Towel! Towel!
And next! つぎ つぎ つぎ！
And next! Next, next, next!
And the third item is...
Tada! Mie Ayam Bowl!
Mie Ayam! 美味しい美味しい！
Mie Ayam! Delicious, delicious!
As the name suggests, this bowl is perfect for eating Mie Ayam...
...but it's also great for ramen, soup, and all kinds of other dishes.
So I'm sure you'll get lots of use for it. You can use it for anything!
Anything!
You can even put cat food into it!
You can even use it as a hat!
Whatever works!
Yeah, I hope this bowl helps you enjoy lots of tasty meals!
Very nice!
And last but certainly not least, the fourth item—just kidding, it's not last, it's the fourth item.
But I was assigned number four because I am a Shinigami.
The fourth item is the Lovely Travel Partner Plushie Keychain!
It is the perfect size to bring on all your trips and your adventures!
Take this adorable little Reine in her costume with you wherever you go and have lots of fun together!
Yay! 素晴らしい！
Yay! Wonderful!
Yay! And this time, I also have a special situational voice:
"Spooky travel partner!"
It includes scary stories recorded in three languages!
Three? Multilingual is so scary!
English, Indonesian. No mixed voice this time, sorry, no mixed language voice.
And of course, the full set comes with an exclusive postcard bonus!
Don't miss out!
We also have a limited number of postcards with my handwritten signature...
...so make sure you don't miss out on this chance!
I want Reine's autograph! I want Reine's autograph!
Hey, no! Me! Me first! I'm gonna buy real fast!
Can you beat Mori Calliope's speed?
Definitely not!
But I'll see you guys in the pit, let's go! Fighting for Reine's signature!
Didn't we already fight enough?
Well, I wanna fight the fans now!
Yeah, it's their turn now! You guys are next!
And that wraps up our merch introduction!
Okay, move! Back, back, back!
Back where? I forgot where I was! I don't know where I was!
Okay guys, phew! This year's birthday celebration was so much fun!
I got to go to two different location shoots...
...spend time with everyone, and make so many great memories!
So thank you, thank you so much again for making my birthday so fun!
You're welcome! Bring it in!
Reine is one year older! One year older!
Congrats on getting closer to me!
Your hair's turning gray! Yours is too!
And now, before we know it, we've reached the final part of this stream...
...and it is time for the new song performance!
Wait, hold on, I gotta show you something! I'm gonna get something!
What is she getting?
Is that what I think it is? My beautiful, beautiful baby!
Bass! It's the Reine bass!
Love the stickers! You guys recognize these stickers?
All right, I worked really, really hard on this song, so I hope you all can enjoy it!
All right, can everyone say the title of the new song together with me?
せーの！ Endless Blue!
Ready, set... Endless Blue!
Endless Blue / 作詞：藤原優樹 作曲・編曲：長谷川大介
[Title: Endless Blue / Lyrics: Yuki Fujiwara / Composition & Arrangement: Daisuke Hasegawa]
飾り付けた言葉でなんて
With decorated words,
本当の鼓動隠してたんだ
I was hiding my true heartbeat.
折りたたんだ羽は
My folded wings
見えない空に焦がれてたんだ
were yearning for an unseen sky.
外れるなら壊してしまった
If it was off, I ended up breaking it,
散らばる欠片 バラバラ
the scattered fragments all scattered about.
誰かに似た色じゃ
A color similar to someone else's...
意味がない わかってるから
...has no meaning, because I know that.
旅立ちはあの青空のせいだ
This departure is all thanks to that blue sky.
誤魔化せない
I can't play dumb,
憧れに気づいたから
because I've realized my longing.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable impulse,
動き出したストーリーの先には
beyond the story that has begun to move...
不安も物思いさえも染めていく
...even anxiety and contemplation are painted over.
想像より今眩しい空が広がってるはずでしょう
A sky brighter than imagination must be spreading out right now, right?
扉を開け行こう
Let's open the door and go.
ヤミヤミ沈む昨日 Love Me Love Me叫び痛む今日も
Darkly sinking yesterday, crying "Love Me" in pain today too,
今更なんて言ってた願いの色はくすんでいた
the color of wishes I deemed "too late now" had faded.
痛みなら飲み干してしまおう
If it's pain, let's swallow it all down.
また乗り越えてみせるよ
I'll show you I can overcome it again.
私でいることにためらう弱さはもういらない
I no longer need the weakness of hesitating to be myself.
広げた羽は飾りじゃないよ
These spread wings aren't for decoration.
鮮やかな夢を纏おう
Let's adorn ourselves with vivid dreams.
その覚悟がここにあるから
Because that determination is right here.
幻想の夜重ねて
Overlaying nights of illusion,
ぶらり漂うように歩いていたよ
I was walking as if drifting aimlessly.
途方案なく遠くて挫けそうになっても
Even if it's hopelessly far and I feel like giving up,
この声は羽ばたけるその時を待っていたんだ
this voice was waiting for the moment it could take flight.
もう一度叫んでみるよ
I'll try shouting once more.
終わりなんてない旅を続けたくて
Wanting to continue a journey that has no end,
進んでいくストーリーの向こうへと
toward the other side of the advancing story...
この声で果てない空を渡っていく
...with this voice, I'll cross the endless sky.
まだ知らない遥かな青に
Toward an as-yet-unknown, distant blue,
胸を膨らませて
with my heart swelling,
無限の明日がきっと待ってるから
because an infinite tomorrow is surely waiting.
扉を開け行こう
Let's open the door and go.